Who are you?
They're right here.
Hurry and move the firewood!
Hurry!
Come help!
Hold on.
If they're really hiding in there...
...isn't doing this a bit impolite?
Stop going on and on about female ghosts.
There are no ghosts.
There really is a ghost in the Li Mansion!
My master and I saw it with our own eyes!
You've really seen a ghost?
It's the absolute truth!
That female ghost was covered in blood...
...and absolutely terrifying!
They aren't ghosts at all.
They're human.
Three living, breathing people.
The ghost was barely an inch away from me.
I could feel her breath,
her body heat,
and I could even smell
the powder on their faces.
When I thought about it later,
I was certain.
The so-called ghosts in the Li Mansion
were all just people in disguise.
See?
I told you
they weren't ghosts.
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
I was nearly scared to death!
Since
they want to put on a show,
we'll play along
and be the audience
to watch the spectacle.
Watch out!
I had no idea
you hid your skills so well.
You're pretty good.
The magic trick you want to see
is right inside.
The First Madam's white dress.
The Second Madam's Western dress.
The Third Madam's costume.
The ghosts were actually people in disguise.
This is the rouge the First Madam used on her face.
It has a high proportion of talcum powder.
It's whiter than normal foundation.
Specifically for theater troupes.
And what's inside this bottle...
is red pigment made from cochineal.
The blood on the Second Madam's head...
was exactly this.
What is this?
This nail guard...
is what the Third Madam...
used as the ghost hand to scare Master Li.
The women in the Li Mansion...
are only Chunmei and the shaman.
And the servants are all men.
So who played these three ghosts?
Demoness.
We just arrived in Lijia Town.
We don't know much about this place.
Did any theater troupes come to town to perform?
Last year.
Last year, there was a...
Western magic troupe that came here.
Later, a Peking opera troupe and a Kunqu opera troupe came.
What about last month?
Which was...
after the three madams died.
Did any troupes come then?
Last month...
I remember now.
An acrobatics troupe came.
Let me tell you, they...
They are from the acrobatics troupe.
Furthermore,
they are masters in the Art of disguise.
The so-called Art of disguise...
can alter bone structure and conceal the skin.
Eyebrows and eyes can be drawn.
Wrinkles can be added.
That's how they used makeup and the Art of disguise
to disguise themselves as female ghosts.
They played the female ghosts!
If the ghosts were played by people...
Where did those strange noises at night come from?
Run!
The ghost is here!
A Gramophone recording?
It wasn't a recording.
A Gramophone has a single sound source,
but these strange sounds...
came from all directions.
Then where did the sounds come from?
Sound is produced...
by the vibration of objects.
So we should search the entire mansion
thoroughly.
See if there's anything unusual.
Then we can find the source of these strange sounds.
What exactly are we looking for?
Look for small holes.
Small holes?
Master.
Are these the small holes you mentioned?
Exactly.
It's these...
round holes piercing through the walls.
There are nine small holes in total here.
Why would they drill holes in the wall?
What's the principle behind this?
The strange sounds being produced...
originated from these small holes.
These small holes can make sounds?
Have you ever played a harmonica?
According to the construction principles of the Classic of Lu Ban,
they turned the Li Mansion
into a giant harmonica.
The outer walls are higher than the inner courtyard,
which facilitates air resonance.
They also carved
small holes like these into the walls,
just like the sound holes in a harmonica.
When the north wind blows through,
the wind causes resonance,
which produces these strange sounds.
Madam.
You're finally back.
I was worried sick.
Where did you run off to?
What do you care where I went?
Madam, the auspicious hour is near.
Let's hurry up and perform the wedding ceremony.
Benefactor Li.
Don't you want to know who wants to kill you?
Madam...
You found the killer?
At this very moment,
the killer is in the Li Mansion.
We've already searched outside.
Only the inside is left.
The Li Mansion is your home.
Search all you want.
This silver needle
is the hidden weapon used to assassinate Mengzhu.
Earlier,
it was used on the Zhong Kui puppet.
And in the woods,
Watch out!
it was the weapon used to assassinate me.
These paints and brushes
were used by the killer to paint the boy's portrait.
He's over there!
And this pair of shoes
matches the shape of the shoes found at the crime scene,
as well as the sole patterns
perfectly.
The killer
was wearing these exact shoes
when attempting to assassinate me.
All these items
were found in Chunmei's room.
Before Mengzhu and the three madams died,
they were all served by Chunmei.
Therefore,
the killer
is Chunmei.
Oh, Chunmei,
I've always treated you so well.
Why did you kill Mengzhu and the others?
Could someone be framing Chunmei?
Chunmei,
you're suspected of killing four women in the Li Mansion,
and making multiple failed attempts on Jiang Huai's life.
Come with me to the police station.
I want to turn myself in.
I want to turn myself in too.
Dazhu, Erzhu.
What does this have to do with you?
Hurry back!
Why is it you guys?
Inspector,
you've arrested the wrong person.
Chunmei is just a weak woman.
She couldn't kill anyone.
I killed the madams and the young lady.
Let Chunmei go.
You're not the stuttering Erzhu.
Inspector Mu,
don't listen to his nonsense.
He doesn't have what it takes to kill anyone.
I killed them.
Big brother.
The one who tried to assassinate Jiang Huai
was also me.
You're not the submissive Dazhu.
What do you mean, submissive?
I can see he has profound inner strength.
He must be the best martial artist in the Li Mansion, right?
That's right.
The eldest brother, Dazhu,
a security guard at the furniture factory.
He's highly skilled,
and excels in woodworking and painting.
The second brother, Erzhu,
is a worker at the chemical plant.
Besides growing flowers,
he also knows how to make Caustic Soda.
The third sister, Chunmei,
is a female worker at the textile mill.
She excels at sewing.
The madams of the Li Mansion
trusted her deeply.
It was the three of them
who collaborated from the inside and out to commit the crimes.
Jiang Huai,
you really are a brilliant strategist.
You three, come with me to the police station.
Wait.
Don't forget,
there are still some who slipped through the net.
There's someone else?
The three female ghosts.
Come out on your own.